<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of the cow-keepers, within the weekly Bills of Mortality, in relation to the Bill now depending before this honourable House, for the better regulating select vestries.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01900</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1057</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC T11169</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99834158</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99834158</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175512</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01900)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175512)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2739:22, 21242:72)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of the cow-keepers, within the weekly Bills of Mortality, in relation to the Bill now depending before this honourable House, for the better regulating select vestries.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Publication data suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Requesting provision in the Bill for a lesser rate upon land within the Bills of Mortality.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the originals in the British Library and the Lincoln's Inn Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Pasture, Right of --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Cattle trade --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:175512:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <hi>THE CASE OF THE</hi> Cow-keepers, within the Weekly Bills of Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tality, in Relation to the <hi>BILL</hi> now De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending before this Honourable Houſe, <hi>For the better Regulating Select Veſtries.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THAT it is too well known, how the Poors Rates have increaſed of late Years, and what very great Loſſes the <hi>Cow-keepers</hi> have lately ſuſtained; Indeed they have ſuffered ſo much, that they wou'd inevitably been Ruined, had not His MAJESTY been Graciouſly Pleaſed to have been Bountiful to them.</p>
            <p>THAT by the <hi>Bill</hi> now Depending, it is Humbly Conceiv'd, That <hi>all Houſes, Lands, and Perſonal Eſtates, will be Charged with an equal Pound Rate,</hi> which will be a very heavy Burthen, not upon the Land-Owners, but upon the <hi>Land-Holders</hi> (eſpecially the <hi>Cow-keepers</hi>) within the Weekly Bills of Mortality; and if the <hi>Cow-keepers</hi> are made liable to this Charge, they will not be able to follow their Imployments, ſo abſolutely neceſſary for the Supplying the Cities of <hi>London, Weſtminſter,</hi> Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> and Suburbs thereof; For the Rent of ſuch Land, as lies within the Weekly Bills of Mortality, is very high, and the moſt Conſiderable Return, a <hi>Tenant</hi> or <hi>Land-Holder</hi> can make from ſuch Land, is by the Stock kept thereupon; ſo 'tis Humbly Hop'd, That Stock upon Land ſhall be Exempted out of the preſent <hi>Bill</hi> Depending, the Legiſlator having thought fit <hi>to Exempt all Stock upon Land, from the Tax laid upon Perſonal Eſtates, by Virtue of the ſeveral Acts paſt, for Raiſing Money by a Land-Tax,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>THAT ſince all the Land, or the greateſt Part of it, within the Weekly Bills of Mortality, is generally held by long Leaſes, from the Land-Owners, the <hi>Tenants</hi> will be obliged to Pay the <hi>Pound Rate,</hi> ſo intended to be laid upon Land, whereby they will Pay almoſt a double Tax; which the ſeveral Pariſhes muſt unavoidably lay upon the <hi>Cow-keepers,</hi> unleſs Proviſion be made in the <hi>Bill,</hi> That the Land may bear only a Proportion, of Two Third Parts to the Charge upon Houſes; which has been Practiſed for ſeveral Years, in ſuch Pariſhes, where a Pound Rate has been laid, for Raiſing the Poors Rates.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>IT is Humbly Pray'd, That this Honourable Houſe will be pleaſed to take into Conſideration the great Loſſes the</hi> COW-KEEPERS <hi>have ſuſtained, and the many Debts they have incurred by Reaſon thereof, and what Hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips they will be under, if the</hi> Bill <hi>aforeſaid ſhou'd Paſs, as it is now drawn, and to give them ſuch Relief, as to Your</hi> Honours <hi>ſhall ſeem Reaſonable.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>AND they will ever Pray,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:175512:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:175512:2"/>
            <p>
               <hi>THE CASE OF THE</hi> Cow-keepers, within the Weekly Bills of Mortality, in Relation to the <hi>BILL,</hi> now Depending before this Honourable Houſe, <hi>For the better Regulating Select Veſtries.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
